# Jason Ng

# Software Engineer

**★** jasonkng.dev **in** jasonkngdev **③** jasonkngdev **③** gmail.com **⑤** jason-ng3 **⑤** New York, NY

#### **PROFILE**

I'm a voracious learner and resilient problem solver with multiple years of experience in the JavaScript and Ruby ecosystems, as well as Docker and Infrastructure-as-Code deployments using AWS. Most recently, I built Canopy, an open-source low-config monitoring framework, designed specifically for CDNs.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Software Engineer, Creator, Canopy, (canopy-framework.github.io)

04/2023 - present

- Architected an end-to-end pipeline for streaming Amazon CloudFront CDN logs to ClickHouse and visualizing metrics on real-time dashboards in Grafana, making it easier for developers to debug their CDN traffic
- Reduced buffering latency to a customizable amount (as low as 0 milliseconds) via a custom streaming solution engineered in AWS Lambda
- Implemented a buffer for re-streaming and retrying failed logs using AWS Lambda and Kinesis Data Streams, and a dead-letter queue using AWS SQS for routing failed logs to persistent storage
- Containerized and configured Canopy's backend infrastructure, including Vector, ClickHouse and Grafana for deployment on a single Docker network
- Implemented native support for monitoring parallel CloudFront distributions by automating their attachment and detachment to and from the pipeline, while tracking their meta-data with SQLite
- Automated 50+ AWS steps down to a single deploy command by writing AWS CDK code and deploying CloudFormation stacks
- Created a CLI to facilitate configuration, deployment, and teardown of the pipeline
- Collaborated remotely with a team of four software engineers across multiple time zones
- Authored a technical case study on Canopy's problem domain, architecture, challenges and design decisions (canopy-framework.github.io ∅)

#### **Software Engineer,** Open-Source Contributor

11/2021 - 04/2023

Developed open-source web applications, some highlights projects include:

- Request Warehouse: a real-time tool for debugging and testing webhooks (Node.js, Express, React, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, WebSockets)
- Done & Done: an interactive to-do list manager (Node.js, Express, SQLite, JavaScript, HTML, CSS)
- My Cookbook: a personal recipe keeper organized by cuisine (Ruby, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS)

# Futures Trader, Self-Employed

2011 - 2021

• Executed split-second decisions for trading index futures, based on technical analysis of volatility chart patterns, order flow, momentum of price movement and market conditions.

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Backend**

Ruby, Node.js, Express, Sinatra, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, ClickHouse, WebSockets, RESTful APIs

## **Frontend**

JavaScript, React, Jest, jQuery, HTML, CSS

#### Cloud

AWS: CDK, SDK, EC2, CloudFront, Kinesis Data Streams, Firehose, S3, SQS, Lambda, IAM, VPC, CloudFormation, ECS; DigitalOcean Droplets; Heroku

### Other Technologies

Docker, Git, GitHub, Grafana, Linux, Bash, Nginx

# **EDUCATION**

Launch School, Software Engineering & Full-Stack Development

11/2021 - 04/2023